Hi everyone, I'm Susie Woo
大家好 我是戴舒萱
I'm from the UK
我来自英国
Welcome back to my channel
欢迎回到我的频道
It's another enrolment period for our
现在又到了全方位英语文化课程报名期间
Learn English Through UK Culture Course
So for you intermediate
所以如果你是中级到高级的英文学习者
to advanced English learners
who want to improve your English
而且你想提升你的英文
in the most effective
用最有效率
and the most interesting way possible,
也最有趣的方式
you can join now
你现在就可以加入
But there are limited places
但是名额有限
and there's only a limited period of time
而且可以报名的时间
that you can sign up
也只有短短一段期间
So if you enjoy today's video head to
所以如果你喜欢今天这支影片 就到
to check it out
看看吧
So boys and girls,
好啦 各位同学们
what are we learning about today?
我们今天要学什么呢?
We're going to talk about
我们今天要来聊
We're going to talk about relationships and dating
我们今天要来聊关系和约会
This lesson has been taught
这堂课其实已经在Susiewoo语言学校教过了
at Susie Woo language school,
这堂课其实已经在Susie Woo语言学校教过了
but it is not in our full annual curriculum
但它没有被放进我们完整的年度课程里
into British life and culture,
也就是那套深入英国生活与文化的课程中
where we've condensed and optimised our best
在那套课里 我们把最好的
learning materials into a year of learning for you
学习材料浓缩优化成一整年的学习内容
But I thought it would still give you a nice insight
但我想这堂课还是能让你很好地了解
into the kinds of things that we do
我们平常都在做些什么
So relationships and dating, part one
所以 关系与约会 第一部分
We have an alternating rota
我们的作业类型会轮流安排
of the types of homework
Sometimes it's speaking,
有时候是口说
so you need to do some research
所以你需要先做一些研究
and prepare something to say in class
然后准备一些东西在课堂上说
for just a few minutes
大概讲几分钟就可以了
Sometimes it's reading comprehension,
有时则是阅读理解
but what we will always have is
但每一堂课一定都会有的是
a video homework at the start of each class
课堂开始的一个影片作业
to get the discussion going
让我们可以在课堂前讨论
So in this case, we would
所以像这堂课 一开始我们会先让你
start the lesson with you
either discussing a famous British building,
讨论一个有名的英国建筑
car or fashion brand,
汽车或服装品牌
so that would relate to last week's topic
因为那会和上周的主题有关
Or you could focus on a particular design
或者你也可以改成介绍某个特定设计
or designer from your own country
或你自己国家的设计师
Or we're pretty flexible
或者其实我们也很弹性
You can talk about anything that you want
你想讲什么都可以
It's a chance for you to speak and get feedback
这是让你开口说英文
from qualified teachers on your speaking
并获得由合格的老师给你口说回馈的机会
So I'm gonna skip over the video homework
所以我今天会先跳过那个影片作业
because for copyright reasons
因为版权的关系
I can't show you the video in this video,
我没办法在这支影片里播放那段影片
so let's just go through that
所以这部分我们就先略过
But what I do want to share with you
但我真的很想跟你分享的是
is the meaning of the ick
“the ick”这个词的意思
To get the ick
This is a very specific phrase
这是一个非常特定的说法
that people are using at the moment for dating
现在很多人在约会时都会用
It's like they start to get to know someone
意思是你开始认识某个人
and they think
然后心里觉得
oh, this person
喔 这个人
seems quite nice, quite interesting
好像蛮不错的 也蛮有趣的
Maybe I like them
也许我喜欢他
And then for some reason, something changes,
但不知道为什么 突然有什么东西变了
something happens where you suddenly think,
发生了一件事让你突然间觉得
oh no, I don't like this person
喔不 我不喜欢这个人了
And it can be the stupidest silliest thing
而且那个原因可能超蠢又超微不足道
like maybe they have a velcro wallet
比如说他用魔鬼毡皮夹
or they slurp when they drink through a straw
或者他用吸管喝东西时会发出吸溜声
It can be honestly the most mundane of things
真的可能只是最平凡最无聊的小事
and that's kind of the joke with the ick
而这就是“the ick”这个词好笑的地方
is that it doesn't have to be a real reason
就是你根本不需要有什么真正的理由
not to like someone
去不喜欢一个人
You can just not like someone
你可以因为任何莫名其妙的理由就不喜欢对方
for whatever reason at all
It just describes that moment
它只是拿来描述那个瞬间
when you suddenly think, ew
就是你突然心里想 噁
no, I don't like this person
不行 我不喜欢这个人
That is the ick
那就是the ick
Right, so lesson objectives for today are
好 所以今天这堂课的学习目标是
to learn about relationships
了解英国的感情和约会文化
and dating culture in the UK
Try your hand at being an agony aunt
试着扮演一个“agony aunt”
We'll find out what that means
我们等一下会解释那是什么意思
and as always learn more useful
还有一如往常地再学更多实用的
everyday phrases and vocabulary
日常片语和单字
Every week, there are 15 of these
每一周我们都会有15个这样的单字
that we've specifically chosen
而且都是我们特别挑选过的
because they're so useful
因为它们真的非常实用
and so commonly used
也非常常用
especially in the UK
尤其是在英国
So you come away from each lesson
所以你每上完一堂课
with concrete words and phrases
都会带走一些很具体的单字和片语
that you can start to use in your speaking
而且你可以立刻用在自己的口说里
Now, this lesson starts with a bit of a discussion
好 这堂课一开始会先进行一些讨论
How would you describe
你会怎么形容你国家的约会文化?
the dating scene in your country?
So the dating scene is like how people date
“dating scene”指的就是人们是怎么约会的
Is it relaxed?
是很轻松的吗?
Is it quite strict?
还是很严格?
Maybe if you're from India, for example,
假如你来自印度
there might be specific arrangements
可能就会有一些特定安排
Maybe your family needs to attend the dates
也许你的家人需要一起参加约会
or maybe it's totally carefree
或者也可能是完全自由随性的
and you can do whatever you want
你想怎么做都可以
Do you think it's the same
你觉得和英国的约会文化
or different to dating culture in the UK?
是一样还是不一样的?
So we'll be talking about that in this lesson
所以这堂课里我们就会谈这个
and the last question for everyone to discuss
最后一个给大家3人一组
in their small groups of three with the teacher is
和老师一起在小组里讨论的问题是
do you watch any dating shows
你会看任何约会实境秀吗
What's your favourite one?
你最喜欢哪一个?
And we will come to this shortly
我们等一下就会讲到这个
Here, we have four words at the bottom
这里底下有四个单字
and we need to fill the blanks
我们要把它们填进空格里
We have
我们有
We have outright, spontaneously,
我们有 outright spontaneously
banter and cheesy
banter 和 cheesy
Now, you may not know what these words mean
你现在可能还不知道这些字是什么意思
Let's talk about them
我们来讲讲它们
Neither men nor women
不管男生还是女生
stop each other on the street
都不会在街上拦住彼此
declare their love from across the road
隔着马路就大声告白
___ ask someone out
___ 约某个人出去
So ask someone out is highlighted
“ask someone out”这个片语被特别标示出来了
as one of the key phrases
因为它是我们这周要学的重要片语之一
for us to learn this week
To ask someone out
means to ask them on a date
意思就是约对方出去约会
For example,
比如说
hey, would you like to
嘿 你想不想
get coffee with me sometime
哪天跟我一起去喝杯咖啡?
meaning I want to date you
意思就是我想跟你约会
So because this starts with the verb ask,
因为这句话前面是动词 ask
before that verb,
所以在那个动词前面
we probably need something like an adverb
我们大概会需要一个像副词一样的东西
if you remember adverbs
如果你还记得副词
end with y usually or ly
通常会以y或ly结尾
So it could be maybe cheesy or spontaneously
所以这里可能是 cheesy 或 spontaneously
Now, spontaneously is like being proactive
那spontaneously就有点像主动
Like proactively going over
就是你主动走过去
and asking someone
然后去问一个人
You just have that feeling of
你就是有那种感觉
oh yeah, I'm gonna do this
喔对 我要去做这件事
I'm not thinking about it too much
我没有想太多
I'm just gonna ask that girl out
我就是要去约那个女生
So this sentence is saying that in the UK,
所以这句话其实是在说 在英国
both men and women do not do this
不管男生还是女生都不会这样做
We are not very spontaneous in our dating
我们在约会这件事上并不是那么主动
So anyway, the missing word is spontaneously
所以这一题的答案是 spontaneously
In Paris, love is practiced as a sport
在巴黎 爱情像是一种运动一样被实践
at any given moment
在任何时刻都是如此
So it's a bit of a joke saying that in France,
所以这句有点像开玩笑地说 在法国
people are romantic all the time
人们随时随地都很浪漫
But over in Britain,
但在英国这边
all that seems ___
这一切看起来就会显得___
if not problematic
甚至是有问题的
Even eye contact is risky
甚至连眼神接触都很危险
Here if not problematic means
这里“if not problematic”的意思是
if it's not this first adjective,
如果它还不至于是前面那个形容词
then it's definitely the second
那至少也绝对是后面这个
If not ___
如果不是___
If not problematic means
If not problematic的意思就是
that it could even seem problematic
它甚至可能已经看起来像个问题了
So the missing word is cheesy
所以这一题缺的字是 cheesy
Cheesy means like cringey
Cheesy的意思有点像尴尬
Like awkward or try-hard
像尴尬或做作
Like overly romantic,
就是过度浪漫
but with that cringey over the top feeling
但又带着那种过头又让人尴尬的感觉
like wow that's too much
像是 哦 太过分了
So it's like too much, too romantic
就是太多了 太浪漫了
That's cheesy
那就叫cheesy
Nothing to do with actual cheese
跟真的起司一点关系都没有
So in Britain, being very romantic,
所以在英国 如果你非常浪漫
can be seen as cheesy
就可能会被看成“cheesy”
and even more than that
而且还不只如此
it could be seen as problematic
甚至可能会被视为有问题
Like it is a problem
像是真的成了一个问题
and the last bit is an exaggeration
而后面那句其实是夸张说法
Even eye contact is risky
甚至连对视都很危险
It's saying we are so avoidant of romance
它是在说我们对浪漫这件事回避到一种程度
that we don't even like
连互相看着对方眼睛都不太敢
to look each other in the eye
Obviously, that's not really true
当然 这不是真的字面意思
That's just an exaggeration
那只是夸张的讲法
Like a little joke
就是个小玩笑
In the UK, I sometimes leave a date
在英国 我有时候约会结束后会觉得
thinking he doesn't like me,
他根本不喜欢我
but it turns out that he does
但结果事实上他其实喜欢我
British men won't tell you their feelings ___
英国男生不会___告诉你他们的感受
We have outright or banter
我们这里有outright和banter
We could also use the word spontaneously here
其实这里也可以用spontaneously
That would also be fine
那样也说得通
Or we could also say
或者我们也可以说
British men won't tell you their feelings outright
英国男生不会这么直接地告诉你他们的感受
Outright here means directly
这里outright的意思就是直接地
Like a very direct confession
像很直接的告白
British people do not confess to you that easily
英国人不会这么简单地向你告白
Confessing your feelings
告白在英国不是这么简单的事情
is not that simple in the UK
Men usually will not say it so directly
男生通常不会这么直接说
So what do they do?
那他们会怎么做?
Instead sarcasm and banter
反而会用讽刺和“banter”
So what is banter?
那banter是什么?
It's like playful teasing
它有点像带着玩笑的逗弄
Like making fun of the other person
就是开对方玩笑
They might tease you
可能会取笑你
Like little jokes
像一些小玩笑
Like taking a dig or a poke at you
像是轻轻酸你一下 或戳你一下
Making fun of you in a light hearted, fun way
用很轻松好玩的方式闹你
So it's supposed to be funny
所以它的本意是好笑的
And this type of humour is often seen as flirting
而这种幽默通常会被看成是在调情
And flirting is that behaviour that you do
而flirting就是那种
when you like someone
当你喜欢某个人你会做出的行为
Like hehehe
像是嘿嘿嘿
When there's that chemistry and vibe
当两个人之间有那种化学反应或氛围
between two people who maybe like each other
也就是彼此可能互相喜欢的感觉
and then there's flirting
那就会出现“flirting”
Next page here, we have three words
接下来这一页我们有三个字
Chat, move and date
Chat move 和 date
After an online discussion
在一段线上聊过之后
that feels more like a ___ with a coworker
感觉比较像是跟同事的___
We could say like a chat with a coworker
这里可以说比较像是跟同事聊天
You finally agree to meet for a drink
最后你们终于同意出去喝一杯
Never ever call it a ___
但千万不要把它叫做___
date
约会
Again, this is a bit of a joke
这一样有点是在开玩笑
It shows how avoidant British people are
它在表现英国人到底有多逃避
It might clearly be a sign of interest
明明聊天后和对方一起去喝一杯
in the other person
to go for a drink with them after chatting
很可能是对方对你感兴趣的明显讯号
But we would not say it's a date
但我们还是不会说那是约会
because we're afraid of that word
因为我们害怕那个字
It feels too serious
那个字听起来太认真了
People want to pretend like,
大家会想假装成
No no no, it's just casual
没有没有 这很随意的
Almost like we're just friends,
就好像我们只是朋友而已
so then if it goes badly
这样如果最后不顺利
You can't say
你也不用说
oh, the date went badly
喔 这场约会很糟
It's more like oh, you know,
你就可以说 喔 你知道的
I just had a chat with someone
我只是跟某人聊了聊
and I'm not going to see them again,
然后我不会再见他了
but I didn't like them anyway
反正我本来也不喜欢他
So people are very shy and embarrassed
所以大家对表露感情这件事很害羞也很别扭
to let others know our feelings,
不太想让别人知道自己的感受
which is why you might not often
这也是为什么你不太常会
hear people say that it's a date
听到人们直接说那是约会
They don't want to reveal that
因为他们不想透露
they actually like the other person
自己其实真的喜欢对方
I know it's a bit stupid
我知道这有点蠢
and not everyone is like this
而且也不是每个人都这样
Alcohol is ordered the very second you meet
你们一见面就会立刻点酒
That means like that exact moment
意思就是那个时刻
At that moment
就在那一刻
You meet and then bam, alcohol
一见面 然后砰 先来酒
In the largest volumes available
而且还要点能点到的最大份量
Again, exaggeration, kind of a joke
一样是夸张说法 有点搞笑
and consumed as fast as possible
然后还要用最快速度喝掉
So you get the idea
所以你大概懂那个画面了
Brits meet, they're like,
英国人一见面就会想
oh, awkward
喔 好尴尬
Need to drink a lot of alcohol immediately
得立刻喝很多酒才行
But nobody ever makes a ___
但没有人真的会去___
Move
行动
So what is to make a move
那to make a move是什么意思?
and why does nobody ever
还有为什么在英国几乎没人make a move?
make a move in the UK
no matter how drunk you are
不管你喝得多醉都一样
Making a move is like going to the next level
Making a move就是把事情往下一步推
So maybe like touching the other person
比如说去碰一下对方
or saying I like you
或者直接说我喜欢你
or maybe kissing them
或者干脆亲下去
or something that shows actual affection
总之就是做出某种真的表达好感的举动
and like you actually like them
让人知道你是真的喜欢对方
Again, this is just emphasising the fact
这一样是在强调一件事
that British people can be quite shy and awkward
就是英国人真的可以很害羞 很尴尬
and avoidant of showing their feelings
而且很逃避表露自己的感受
So we're starting to get an idea of
所以我们现在开始有点理解了
what dating is really like in the UK
英国的约会文化到底实际是什么样子
And if we were in a real class I might ask you
如果这是在真的课堂上 我这时候就会问你
is being sarcastic or teasing someone
在你的国家 用讽刺或闹对方
seen as flirting in your country?
会被看成是在调情吗?
Are people awkward about the terms they use?
大家会对用词感到尴尬吗?
Like the word date
像是约会
And would someone ask
而且在街上会有人直接约别人出去吗?
someone else out on the street?
Are people bold and brave
你们国家的人都很大胆很勇敢吗?
like that in your country?
Obviously, we're mostly thinking of the US
当然 我们主要想到的是美国
On American TV anyway,
至少在美剧里
they seem very confident
他们看起来都非常有自信
and okay with asking someone out
而且也很自在地直接约人出去
Like hey, want to go for a drink sometime?
像是 嘿 哪天要不要一起去喝一杯?
That would pretty much never happen in the UK
这种事在英国几乎不会发生
It's all much more quiet, secretive,
英国这边一切都更安静 更隐晦
underhand and confusing
更偷偷摸摸 也更让人困惑
Now, let's learn some
现在我们来学一些和约会有关的实用俚语
useful slang related to dating
Which of these phrases mean either
下面哪些片语表示的是
to end a relationship
结束一段关系
or to kiss someone passionately
或者热情地亲一个人?
So to end a relationship,
好 如果是结束一段关系
we have some words on the right here
右边这里有几个词
To break up with
To make out with
To get off with
To split up with
To neck on
To call it quits
To snog and to dump
To snog 和 to dump
or be dumped by someone
或者 be dumped by someone
As you can see most of them are phrasal verbs
你可以看到 大部分都是片语动词
Phrasal verbs are incredibly common in English,
片语动词在英文里非常非常常见
but they can be difficult to use
但也真的很难用得自然
which is why we need lots of practice
所以我们才需要大量练习
So which ones mean to end a relationship?
所以哪几个是表示分手呢?
We've got to break up with
首先是“to break up with”
That's breaking up
那就是分手
To break up with
分手
He broke up with me
他跟我分手了
and I don't know why
而我不知道为什么
Now to make out with
接下来是“to make out with”
That one means to kiss someone passionately,
这个意思是很激烈地亲一个人
but it's especially American slang, this one
但这个比较偏美式俚语
Oh my god, I saw you guys making out at school
天啊 我看到你们在学校亲得超激烈
That was so gross
真的有够噁
So what would we say in the UK instead?
那在英国我们会怎么说?
We would say get off with
我們會說 get off with
This is very slangy
这个非常口语 很俚语
and something teenagers
而且通常比较像青少年会说的话
would be more likely to say
Like oh yeah, I got off with that girl last night
像是 喔对 我昨晚跟那个女生亲到了
She is well fit, mate
她真的超正 兄弟
How about to split up with?
那“to split up with”呢?
Do you think that means kissing or breaking up?
你觉得这是亲热还是分手?
Well, split is like separating
split本来就有分开的意思
So that is breaking up
所以这个就是分手
You could say that the celebrity couple split up
你可以说 那对名人情侣分手了
That means they ended their relationship
意思就是他们结束关系了
Now, neck on is another way
再来“neck on”也是另一种说法
of saying kiss passionately
表示热情接吻
Especially in the north,
尤其在英国北部
like they were necking on
像是they were necking on
means they were kissing a lot
意思就是他们一直在热吻
Then we have to call it quits
接着是“to call it quits”
that means end a relationship
它的意思是结束一段关系
and it can also mean end other things
而且它也可以用在其他事情上表示结束
Like this game is not going very well
比如说 这场游戏玩得不怎么样
Shall we just call it quits?
我们要不要干脆就算了?
Like just finish
就是直接结束
Now, to snog
再来是to snog
Snog is a funny one
Snog这个词很有意思
It also means kiss passionately
它也是热情接吻的意思
It brings to mind that image of two people like
它会让人联想到两个人那种
You know, just like
你知道 就是亲得超级投入的画面
really going for it with the kissing
Like too much and like a bit gross
有点太多了 而且甚至有点噁
and maybe saliva and stuff like that
还有口水之类的东西
So that's snogging
那就叫snogging
And then to dump or be dumped by
最后是to dump或be dumped by
So you might know that to dump
你可能知道dump这个字本来有
is like to get rid of something
把某样东西丢掉的意思
In the US, they say the word dumpster
在美国还有dumpster这个字
which is like the rubbish bin
就是垃圾桶的意思
where you put your rubbish
你把垃圾丢进去的地方
or trash as they say in the US
或者美国人会说“trash”
So in this case, it is to break up
但在这里它的意思就是分手
Like he dumped me
像是 他甩了我
or I was dumped by him
或者 我被他甩了
Again, it's quite casual slang,
这一样是很口语的俚语
so you won't see this in formal newspapers
所以你不太会在正式报纸里看到这样写
like the Guardian or the Times
像《卫报》或《泰晤士报》
You're more likely to see it
你比较可能会在八卦小报看到
in tabloid newspapers
like the Sun or the Mirror
像《太阳报》或《镜报》
Ooh, okay
喔 OK
Now, we're talking about dating shows
接下来我们来聊约会节目
Have you seen these?
你有看过这些吗?
Married at first sight and Naked attraction
《一见钟情》和《裸体吸引》
Let me tell you what happens in these shows
我来跟你说这些节目里会发生什么
Single people take part in a social experiment,
单身人士会参加一个社会实验
where they are matched with total strangers
在里面他们会和完全陌生的人配对
by psychologists and dating experts
由心理学家和约会专家来配对
So they don't know the person in advance
也就是说他们事先根本不认识对方
and they're just matched together
只是直接被配成一对
They meet for the very first time
他们第一次见面就是在婚礼当天
on their wedding day
and then have six weeks to decide
然后有6周的时间决定
whether to make a go of
到底要不要试着把婚姻经营下去 还是分开
the marriage or separate
So make a go of here means to try it out
这里“make a go of”的意思就是试着做做看
Try the marriage
试着经营这段婚姻
See how it goes
看看会发展成什么样
and you could also say
而且你也可以说
make a go of the marriage or dump each other
试着经营婚姻 或干脆互甩
or call it quits or split up
或者到此为止或分开
All means the same thing
意思其实都差不多
So how would you feel
那你会有什么感觉?
if you met someone for the first day
如果你第一次见到某个人
on your wedding day
就是在你婚礼当天
Like it's an arranged marriage
就像安排好的婚姻一样
You meet them,
你见到对方
boom, you're married
砰 然后你就结婚了
Would that be uncomfortable?
那会不会很不舒服?
So in this show,
所以在这个节目里
obviously, it is quite uncomfortable
很明显地这真的会很尴尬
when they see each other
当他们第一次看到彼此时
and they might be like
他们可能会心里想
oh, I am not attracted to this person at all
喔 我对这个人完全没有吸引力
But now, we are married, yay
但现在我们已经结婚了 耶
Question, would you trust a psychologist
问题是 你会相信心理学家
or dating expert to match you with a partner?
或约会专家帮你配对伴侣吗?
If you are dating, it could be quite helpful
如果你正在找对象 这也许其实还蛮有帮助的
to have someone say, hey, on paper,
因为有人会告诉你 欸 以条件来看
it seems like your personality and stuff
你的个性和各方面
is gonna match with this other person
看起来和这个人很配
Maybe it increases the odds
也许这样会提高机率
that you will like that person
让你更可能喜欢上对方
or maybe these things are very hard to predict
或者也可能这种事其实很难预测
Like on paper,
也许纸面上看起来你们应该会很合
it looks like you guys should get on,
but actually you meet each other and it's like
但实际见面之后却会变成
no, there's not a vibe here
不行 感觉完全不对
Now, what is the show naked attraction?
那《裸体吸引》这个节目到底是什么?
This is a very interesting one
这是一个非常有意思的节目
Worth a watch if you're curious
如果你好奇的话真的值得看一下
Basically, a clothed single person
基本上会有一个穿着衣服的单身者
So someone wearing clothes
也就是一个有穿衣服的人
is presented with a gallery of
站在一排
six naked potential partners
6个裸体的潜在对象面前
So literally someone looking for a partner
也就是一个在找伴侣的人
stands there in clothes
穿着衣服站在那里
and looks around at naked bodies
看着一堆全裸的身体
Just the bodies
只有身体
and they can't see the face
还看不到脸
They are hidden behind booths,
因为这些人站在遮板后面
so they're sort of in a like box or something
有点像被藏在一个个小格子里
Their bodies and faces are gradually revealed
他们的身体和脸会一轮一轮慢慢被揭露
in different rounds from the feet up
从脚开始一路往上揭露
So they start off by just seeing the naked feet
所以一开始只会看到赤裸的脚
and then they see the naked legs
接着看到腿
and then the bum and all of it
再来看到屁股 然后其他部位全部都会看到
Like all the genitals,
包括所有生殖器
so it is quite a shocking show
所以这其实是一个蛮震撼的节目
And then they go up and finally see the face last
最后才会一路揭到脸
At each round, the chooser eliminates
每一轮选择的人都会淘汰掉
one naked person until only two are left
一位裸体参赛者 直到最后只剩两个
So like incredibly rude and harsh, right?
所以这真的超级没礼貌也超残忍 对吧?
It's like oh, don't like your bum
就像是 喔 我不喜欢你的屁股
See ya
掰掰
What a weird idea for a show, right?
这节目的概念超怪 对吧?
The chooser then takes their clothes off
接着那个挑人的人自己也要把衣服脱掉
to make the final choice
然后做出最后选择
So they also don't get away
所以他们也不能一路都穿着衣服
with being clothed the whole time
然后就这样躲过去
They do have to take off their clothes eventually
他们最后还是得把衣服脱掉
So you end up with two naked people
所以最后你会看到两个裸体的人
standing there together
一起站在那里
And they are like
然后他们就像是
now boyfriend and girlfriend or something
好 现在我们算男女朋友了之类的
Very strange, very strange
非常奇怪 真的非常奇怪
So are you surprised that
所以你会惊讶吗?
this is shown on British TV?
这种节目居然会在英国电视上播出?
You might think that should be X rated
你可能会觉得这应该是限制级吧
Like banned
甚至应该被禁播
Is it not like pornographic?
这难道不算色情吗?
Well, it's obviously not porn
不过它当然不算色情片
It's just nudity,
它只是裸体而已
but it's still, I guess, quite inappropriate
但我想它看起来还是蛮不适合的
and shocking to see on TV
而且出现在电视上也蛮令人震惊
Here are some reviews about the show
这里有一些关于这个节目的评论
This show is so body positive
这节目真的非常“body positive”
That means it really celebrates people's bodies
也就是说它真的很肯定各种人的身体
I love that they have regular people
我很喜欢他们找来的是一般人
instead of supermodel body builders
而不是超模或健美选手
The contestants are young and old
参赛者有年轻也有年长的
Fat and thin
有胖有瘦
Fit and flabby
有结实的也有松垮的
Flabby is like when you have fat
Flabby的意思是那种会晃动的松软脂肪感
that kind of wiggles
It just goes to show that looks aren't everything
这刚好证明了外表不是一切
and everyone can be beautiful
而且每个人都可以很美
if they have a positive attitude and are confident
只要他们有正面的态度和自信
It's great to see people approach nudity
看到大家这么自然地看待裸体
so casually and to discuss our bodies
而且这么坦白地谈论我们的身体
so frankly and honestly
我觉得真的很棒
So why does this guy like the show?
所以这个人为什么喜欢这个节目?
Well he likes that it’s realistic
他喜欢的是它很真实
It's not just models and perfect people
不是只有模特儿或完美的人
It's like all sorts of
而是各种各样真实不同的身体
different bodies that, you know
You've got big ones, small ones,
有大的 有小的
fat ones, thin ones
有胖的 有瘦的
Everyone is welcome
每一种都被接受
And they're not openly critical about bodies
而且他们不会公开批评身体
They just try and make it light hearted
他们只是想把它做得轻松一点
and fun and everyone is welcome basically
有趣一点 而且基本上谁都可以被接纳
That's why he likes the show
这就是他喜欢这个节目的原因
Now how about this other person, Ross,
那另外这个叫Ross的人呢?
who gave it one star
他给了这节目一颗星
I'm no prude
我不是什么保守到不行的人
A prude means someone who's very shy
Prude是指那种
about anything to do with like
对性或身体话题很害羞
sexual or bodily things
If they say I am no prude,
如果有人说“I am no prude”
it means I am not a prude
意思就是我不是老古板
But this program removes the mystery
但这个节目把原本的那种神秘感全拿掉了
and the old fashioned romance
还有那种老派浪漫
to meeting a person for the first time
初次见面本来会有的感觉也都没了
It's almost like a cattle market
这几乎就像牲畜市场一样
So all the cows lined up in a row
就像一排牛站在那里
and you need to choose
然后你得挑你想吃哪一只
which one you want to eat
My 86 year old mother in law
我八十六岁的岳母
also watched it
也看了这个节目
Shocked and appalled
她感到又震惊又反感
That's a different way of saying
Appalled就是一种带有负面感受的震惊
shocked in a bad way
That young people would be encouraged
居然会鼓励年轻人
to go to such lengths on a TV show
在电视节目上做到这种程度
probably to get the ratings
大概只是为了收视率吧
So to go to lengths means to make the effort
to go to lengths的意思是花很多力气去做某件事
and to do something
而且是做到超出平常的程度
more than you usually would
We both agree that
我们两个都同意
this is one program to miss in the future
这是未来完全可以跳过不看的节目
So they really did not like it
所以他们是真的很不喜欢
They didn't like the fact that
他们不喜欢的是
people were like parading their bodies around
大家像是在展示自己的身体
to try and get approval from others
想借此得到别人的认可
So who do you agree with more?
所以你比较同意哪一边?
What do you think?
你怎么想?
And this was a news headline, it says
而这是一则新闻标题 它写着
a new low: explicit UK show Naked Attraction
英国露骨节目《裸体吸引》再创新低
causes a stir in the US
在美国引发骚动
So what does this mean?
所以这句话是什么意思?
Well, a new low means
“new low”的意思是
the worst point or lowest level
情况跌到前所未有的低点
ever reached in a behaviour or situation
也就是某种行为或情况达到了最糟的程度
It's like there was bad
就像本来已经够糟了
and then there's really bad
结果现在变得更糟
That's a new low
那就叫 a new low
And you can use this in speaking like
而且你在口说里也可以这样用
oh, I missed the train yesterday,
像是 我昨天错过火车
but today, I missed a flight
但今天我居然错过飞机
That's a new low
这真的是创新低了
and then the adjective explicit
接着explicit这个形容词
means containing very clear
意思是包含非常直接
or detailed sexual content
或非常明确的性内容
It's like too much detail
就是细节多到太过头
You can see everything kind of thing
像是什么都看得到那种感觉
More detail than you want to see
比你想看到的细节还要更多
Especially, like nudity
尤其像裸体这种
Or you might have a song that says it's explicit
或者你也可能看到某首歌标注“explicit”
maybe they use a lot of swear words
可能是因为里面用了很多脏话
and graphic language to do with sex usually
或很露骨的性相关语言
And what does to cause a stir mean?
那“to cause a stir”又是什么意思?
That means to cause excitement, controversy
意思就是引起骚动 争议
or widespread attention
或广泛关注
So like people talking, people being shocked
也就是大家在讨论 大家被吓到
Like a big reaction
一种很大的反应
That's a stir
那就叫stir
So are you surprised that American audiences
所以你会惊讶吗 美国观众
are seen as more prudish than British ones?
竟然被认为比英国人更保守?
So we've got that word prude again
所以我们又回到“prude”这个字
So it's like being shy or awkward
它就是指对某些事很害羞 很尴尬
or embarrassed about bodily or sexual things
或者对身体和性相关话题很不自在
Maybe if we think of stereotypes,
如果讲到刻板印象
we think of Americans
我们可能会觉得美国人
as being more bold and outgoing
比较大胆跟外向
Maybe they would be more comfortable
也许他们应该更能接受
with a show like this
这种节目才对
But actually the headline is saying that
但其实这个标题在说的是
they did not appreciate this show in the US
美国人其实并不买单这个节目
And do you have any sort of show
那你的国家有这种节目吗?
like this in your country?
I would be very surprised if you do to be honest
老实说 如果有我会很惊讶
So there's more to talk about here
所以其实这里还有更多东西可以讲
Agony aunt
知心阿姨
Agony aunt is when you
Agony aunt指的是你写信到报社
write a letter into the newspaper
and someone usually
然后通常会有一位
an older lady who works at the newspaper
在报社工作的年长女士
She'll reply and give you
她会回信并给你感情上的建议
advice on your dating situation
So it's very interesting,
所以这个概念很有趣
but I'm running out of time today
但我今天时间不够了
So I don't think I can finish this lesson now
所以我今天应该没办法把这堂课讲完
As you can see,
你也看得出来
there's lots more interesting content
后面其实还有很多有趣内容
If you like this sort of thing
如果你喜欢这一类的内容
If you want to get stuck into British culture
如果你想更深入英国文化里
and improve your English that way,
并且用这种方式提升你的英文
then I highly highly recommend joining our
那我真的非常非常推荐你加入我们的
Learn English Through UK Culture Course
全方位英语文化课程
It's all this sort of stuff
里面全部都是这种内容
about different topics every week
每周都有不同主题
You can check out the curriculum online
你可以去看看网上的课程大纲
online at Susiewoo.com/culture
在 Susiewoo.com/culture 上
As I said, now is a time that you can enrol,
就像我刚刚说的 现在正是可以报名的时间
but it's a limited time
但时间有限
and there are limited spaces
名额也有限
That's because we have
因为我们只有非常精选的几位老师
a very select few teachers,
who have been carefully chosen by me
而且都是我亲自仔细挑选的
for their excellent chat
因为他们真的很会聊天
and teaching abilities and qualifications
而且教学能力和资历也都很强
So it's great fun
所以整体真的很好玩
I hope you can join us
我希望你能加入我们
It's really practical
这堂课真的非常实用
It's going to get you
它会让你的英文口说进步很多
speaking English much better
and also give you
而且也会让你对语言背后的文化
a broad awareness of the culture
behind the language
有更全面的认识
Which for me is the most interesting part
而这对我来说就是最有趣的部分
So that's all for today
所以今天就先到这里
Thanks for watching
谢谢收看
I'm Susie
我是戴舒萱
See you next time
我们下次见
Oh and by the way,
喔对了 顺便一提
if there's a specific topic
如果你有特别想知道的主题
that you would love to know about
Maybe on this YouTube channel
不管是在这个YouTube频道上
or maybe we can add it to our culture course
还是想加进我们的文化课里
Do let us know
都欢迎告诉我们
You can drop us an email
你可以寄信给我们
or you can drop a comment below this video
或者直接在这支影片下面留言
We love to know what you guys find interesting
我们很想知道你们到底对什么主题有兴趣
Alright, see ya
好啦 掰掰